We'll start with an example.
我们先从一个示例开始
Let's say we're in an office and there are two people,
假设办公室里有两个人
Alex and Brenda, and they're both there the same amount of time.
分别是 Alex 和 Brenda 他们在办公室呆的时间一样久
When they were in the office and we see someone passing by really fast,
当他们在办公室内时 我们看到有个人从面前飞快地路过
we can't tell who it is,
无法判断是谁
but we'd like to take a guess.
但是我们想猜测是谁
So far, with all we know,
到目前为止
all we can infer is that since they're both in the office the same amount of time,
我们只能推断 因为他们在办公室呆的时间一样久
the probability of the person being Alex is
因此 此人是 Alex 的概率是 50%
50 percent and the probability of the person being Brenda is also 50 percent.
是 Brenda 的概率也是 50%
But now, let's try to use more information so we
现在我们尝试利用其他信息
can make a better guess of who the person is.
更准确地猜测此人是谁
When we saw the person running by,
当我们看到此人从面前跑过时
we notice that they were wearing a red sweater.
我们注意到他/她穿的是红色毛衣
So, we'll use that piece of information.
我们将利用这一信息
We've known Alex and Brenda for a while,
我们认识 Alex 和 Brenda 已经有一段时间了
and actually we've noticed that Alex wears a red sweater two days a week,
发现一周内有两天 Alex 会穿红色毛衣
and Brenda wears a red sweater three days a week.
一周内有三天 Brenda 会穿红色毛衣
We don't know which days, but we are sure of this fact.
我们不知道是哪几天 但是确定这一事实
Also, when we say week we mean workweek,
我们说的一周是指工作日
so five days, although at the end this won't matter much.
因此是五天 虽然最终影响不大
So now what we'll do,
现在我们将利用这一信息
is we'll use this piece of information to help us make a better guess.
作出更准确的猜测
First off, since Alex wears a red sweater less than Brenda,
首先 Alex 穿红色毛衣的天数比 Brenda 少
It's easy to imagine that it's a bit less likely that
很容易想象 我们看到的人
the person we saw is Alex than that it is Brenda.
是 Alex 的可能性比 Brenda 要低
But exactly how likely?
但是概率到底有多大呢？
Well, let's say that if we saw a person pass by five times,
假设我们看到有人从面前经过了五次
it would make sense to think that two of this times it was Alex,
那么可以猜测有两次是 Alex
since he wears a red sweater twice a week.
因为一周有两天他会穿红色毛衣
And the other three times it was Brenda,
另外三次是 Brenda
since she wears a red sweater three times a week.
因为一周有三天她会穿红色毛衣
Therefore, from here we can infer that the probabilities are 40 and 60.
因此我们可以推断概率分别是 40% 和 60%
We've used the formation about the color of the sweater to obtain
我们利用毛衣颜色这一信息
better probabilities about who was the person who passed by.
得出了从面前经过的人是谁的概率
This is Bayes' theorem and we'll learn in more in detail in the next few videos.
这种技巧称为贝叶斯定理 我们将在接下来的几个视频中详细学习这一定理
The initial guess we had, the 50/50 guess,
我们一开始的猜测 50/50
is called the prior,
称之为先验概率
since it's all we could infer prior to the new information about the red sweater.
因为在获得红色毛衣这一新信息之前 我们只能这么推断
The final guess we have,
60/40 这一最终猜测结论
the 60/40 guess is called the posterior,
称之为后验概率
since we've inferred it after the new information has arrived.
因为这是在获得新信息之后推断的结论